Finding aid for Mike Wallace CBS/60 Minutes Papers, 1922-2007
Bentley Historical Library
- 60 Minutes Program Files
  - Season XIII, September 1980-September 1981
    - "Dalkon Shield" (contraceptive I.U.D. with dangerous implications) (no transcript; see repeat, August 5, 1984), April 19, 1981
      - Background/Post-Show, 2 folders (Box 21)
      - Transcript (Box 21)
    - "Hollywood on the Potomac" repeat (original air date: February 17, 1974), Transcript, April 26, 1981 (Box 21)
    - "Brother Roloff" repeat (original air date: October 22, 1978), Transcript, May 3, 1981 (Box 22)
    - Transcript (no Mike Wallace stories; Wallace introduces Andy Rooney and reads mail), May 10, 1981 (Box 22)
    - "'Cruel and Unusual...'?" (violence in public schools), May 17, 1981
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 22)
      - Transcript (Box 22)
    - "Bonnie" repeat (original air date: May 11, 1980), Transcript, May 24, 1981 (Box 22)
    - Transcript (no Mike Wallace stories; Wallace introduces Andy Rooney and reads mail), May 31, 1981 (Box 22)
    - "Vernon Jordan" (profile of the Executive Director of the Urban League), June 7, 1981
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 22)
      - Transcript (Box 22)
    - "Rational Suicide" repeat (original air date: October 12, 1980), Transcript, June 14, 1981 (Box 22)
    - Transcript (no Mike Wallace stories; Wallace updates on Iran and reads mail), June 21, 1981 (Box 22)
    - "Chemical Warfare" repeat (original air date: November 16, 1980), Transcript, June 28, 1981 (Box 22)
    - "On the Waterfront" repeat (original air date: September 21, 1980), Transcript, July 5, 1981 (Box 22)
    - "Artie" repeat (original air date: October 19, 1980), Transcript, July 12, 1981 (Box 22)
    - "The Queen of Hearts" repeat (original air date: April 3, 1977), Transcript, July 19, 1981 (Box 22)
    - "'We're in the Money'?" repeat (original air date: December 7, 1980), Transcript, August 2, 1981 (Box 22)
    - "The $77,000 Bill" repeat (original air date: September 28, 1980), Transcript, August 9, 1981 (Box 22)
    - "Itzhak" repeat (original air date: December 21, 1980), Transcript, August 23, 1981 (Box 22)
    - "The Minister of Cocaine" repeat (original air date: March 1, 1981), Transcript, August 30, 1981 (Box 22)
    - "Killer Wheels" repeat (original air date: March 8, 1981), Transcript, September 6, 1981 (Box W3)
    - "Easy Money?" repeat (original air date: March 15, 1981), Transcript, September 20, 1981 (Box 22)
    - "Looking at 60 Minutes" (examination of investigative reporting techniques used by this program), September 27, 1981
      - Background/Post-Show, 2 folders (Box 22)
      - Transcript (Box 22)
  - Season XIV, October 1981-September 1982
    - "Mr. Right to Life" (interview of Congressman Henry Hyde (R-Illinois), a leader of the anti-abortion movement), October 4, 1981
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 22)
      - Transcript (Box 22)
    - "Don't Go Near the Water" (chemical dumping in the Niagara River), October 11, 1981
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 22)
      - Transcript (Box 22)
    - Transcript (no Mike Wallace stories; Wallace introduces Andy Rooney and reads mail), October 18, 1981 (Box 22)
    - "Dirty Old Woman" (profile of Dr. Mary Calderone, Director of the Sex Information and Education Council of the United States), October 25, 1981
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 22)
      - Transcript (Box 22)
    - "I. Magnin File" (alleged age discrimination practices in the I. Magnin department store), November 1, 1981
      - Background (Box 22)
      - Post-Show (Box 22)
      - Transcript (Box 22)
    - "Wanted: Terpil and Korkala" (interview with Frank Terpil, former CIA agent turned advisor to Idi Amin and Muammar Qaddafi, and with Gary Korkala, who with Terpil is wanted by New York State authorities for conspiring to sell arms to terrorists), November 8, 1981
      - Background/Post-Show, 3 folders (Box 23)
      - Transcript (Box 23)
    - Transcript (no Mike Wallace stories; Wallace updates Terpil and Korkala story and reads mail), November 15, 1981 (Box W3)
    - "Goodbye Home Sweet Home" (how borrowers can lose their homes by defaulting on home improvement loans), November 22, 1981
      - Background/Post-Show, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - "On Strike For Their Lives" (striking workers' charges of excessive radiation at a Tennessee munitions plant), November 29, 1981
      - Background/Post-Show, 2 folders (Box 23)
      - Transcript (Box 23)
    - "One Billion Consumers" (renewed production and consumption of consumer goods in China), December 6, 1981
      - Background/Post-Show, 2 folders (Box 23)
      - Transcript (Box 23)
    - Transcript (no Mike Wallace stories; Wallace introduces Andy Rooney and reads mail), December 13, 1981 (Box 23)
    - "The First Lady" (interview with Nancy Reagan), December 20, 1981
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 23)
      - Transcript (Box 23)
    - "Fake" (the production and sale of counterfeit brand name products), December 27, 1981
      - Background/Post-Show, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - "All His Life in Jail" (Edward Sanchez, who has spent 31 of his 33 years in foster homes, reform schools and prisons), January 3, 1982
      - Background/Post-Show, 3 folders (Box 23)
    - Transcript (no Mike Wallace stories; Wallace introduces Andy Rooney and reads mail), January 10, 1982 (Box 23)
    - "Who Killed Malcolm X?" (new information on the murder of Muslim leader Malcolm X), January 17, 1982
      - Background/Post-Show, 2 folders (Box 24)
      - Transcript (Box 24)
    - Transcript (no Mike Wallace stories; Wallace introduces Andy Rooney and reads mail), January 24, 1982 (Box 24)
    - "Madame Ambassador" (interview with United States Ambassador Jeanne Kirkpatrick), January 31, 1982
      - Background/Post-Show, 2 folders (Box 24)
      - Transcript (Box 24)
    - "The Bad Drug" (Selacryn, a hypertension drug kept on the market after reports of serious side-effects), February 7, 1982
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 24)
      - Transcript (Box 24)
    - "The Incompetent Doctor" (problems of identifying a doctor as incompetent and revoking his license, illustrated by the case of Dr. Peter Papallardo), February 14, 1982
      - Background/Post-Show, 2 folders (Box 24)
      - Transcript (Box 24)
    - "Nicaragua" (whether the government of Nicaragua is a dictatorship that assists Communist revolutions in other Central American countries), February 28, 1982
      - Background/Post-Show, 2 folders (Box 24)
      - Transcript (Box 24)
    - "Out of Work" (the closing of a profitable General Electric plant in Ontario, California, and the effect on the community), March 7, 1982
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 24)
      - Transcript (Box 24)
    - "A Modern American Tragedy" (how William Bell, a former manager for Hughes Aircraft Company, sold top secret military information to the Polish government), March 14, 1982
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 24)
      - Transcript (Box 24)
    - Transcript (no Mike Wallace stories; Wallace introduces Andy Rooney and reads mail), March 21, 1982 (Box 24)
    - "The Largest Army in the World" (the military and political changes affecting the army of the People's Republic of China), March 28, 1982
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 24)
      - Transcript (Box 24)
    - "Joel Nelson is Missing" (charges that Nelson, a financier in Los Angeles, bilked investors of twenty million dollars), April 4, 1982
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 24)
      - Transcript (Box 24)
    - "Sullivan vs. Sullivan" (a California court decision awarding a woman a share of her former husband's future income for supporting him while he attended medical school), April 11, 1982
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 24)
      - Transcript (Box 24)
    - "In Your Own Back Yard" (a garbage dump in Port Washington, NY, filled with toxic chemicals that leak into nearby homes), April 25, 1982
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 24)
      - Transcript (Box 24)
    - "Fake" repeat (original air date: December 27, 1981), Transcript, May 2, 1982 (Box 24)
    - "All His Life in Jail" update (original air date: January 3, 1982), Transcript, May 9, 1982 (Box 24)
    - "The Nazi Connection" (why a US agency helped Nazi war criminals settle in this country), May 16, 1982
      - Background (Box 24)
      - Post-Show (Box 24)
    - "Vladimir Horowitz" repeat (original air date: December 26, 1977), Transcript, May 30, 1982 (Box 24)
    - "Wanted: Terpil and Korkala" update (original air date: November 8, 1981), Transcript, June 20, 1982 (Box 25)
    - "Who Killed Malcolm X?" repeat (original air date: January 17, 1982), Transcript, June 27, 1982 (Box 25)
    - "The Bad Drug" update (original air date: February 7, 1982), Transcript, July 4, 1982 (Box 25)
    - "One Billion Consumers" repeat (original air date: December 6, 1981), Transcript, July 18, 1982 (Box 25)
    - "I. Magnin File" repeat (original air date: November 1, 1981), Transcript, July 25, 1982 (Box 25)
    - "Joel Nelson is Missing" repeat, (original air date: April 4, 1982), Transcript, August 1, 1982 (Box 25)
    - "The Invisible Handicap" repeat (original air date: November 28, 1976), Transcript, August 15, 1982 (Box 25)
    - "Time Bomb" repeat (original air date: February 8, 1981), Transcript and Post-Show, August 22, 1982 (Box 25)
    - "A Modern American Tragedy" repeat (original air date: March 14, 1982), Transcript, August 29, 1982 (Box 25)
    - "The Nazi Connection" repeat (original air date: November 16, 1982), Transcript, September 12, 1982 (Box 25)
  - Season XV, September 1982-September 1983
    - "Honor Thy Children" (American men trying to reunite with children they fathered in Vietnam) Transcript (no Background/Post-Show; see update, May 22, 1983), September 19, 1982 (Box 25)
    - "Trouble Brewing" (controversial employment practices of the Coors Brewing Company), September 25, 1982
      (no transcript; see repeat, June 5, 1983)
      - Background (Box 25)
      - Post-Show (Box 25)
    - "Small Town, U.S.A." (the financial struggle of a man in Polo, Illinois to care for his brain-damaged daughter when the town refused to assist him), October 3, 1982
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 25)
      - Transcript (Box 25)
    - "Sting Within a Sting" (a convicted swindler, used by the FBI as an undercover agent in the Abscam investigation, defrauded people of $150,000), October 10, 1982
      - Background/Post-Show, 2 folders (Box 25)
      - Transcript (Box 25)
    - "Warning: Dangerous to Your Health" (the efforts of a Dallas attorney to halt the sale of snub-nosed handguns), October 24, 1982
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 25)
      - Transcript (Box 25)
    - "Good Cop, Bad Cop" (police protection of narcotics dealers in Chicago, and an interview with an undercover officer who helped break up an alleged police drug-selling ring) Background/Post-Show (no transcript; see repeat, June 26, 1983), October 31, 1982 (Box 25)
    - Transcript (no Mike Wallace stories; Wallace introduces Andy Rooney and reads mail), November 7, 1982 (Box 25)
    - "Vietnam '82" (current economic and social problems in Vietnam), November 14, 1982
      - Background/Post-Show, 3 folders (Box 25)
      - Transcript (Box 25)
    - "'Le Terrorisme'" (the upsurge of terrorist killings in Paris and the response of the French police), November 21, 1982
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 25)
      - Transcript (Box 25)
    - "Divorce Catholic Style" (the Roman Catholic Church's policy of annulment and the difficulties encountered by those affected by it), November 28, 1982
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 26)
      - Transcript (Box 26)
    - "Jacobo Timerman" (interview with the exiled Argentinian Jewish writer, who strongly criticizes the policies of Israeli leader Menachem Begin), December 5, 1982
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 26)
      - Transcript (Box 26)
    - Transcript (no Mike Wallace stories; Wallace introduces Andy Rooney and reads mail), December 12, 1982 (Box 26)
    - "The Re-selling of Tylenol" (Johnson & Johnson's efforts to reassure the public that Tylenol is safe) Background/Post-Show, December 19, 1982 (Box 26)
    - "Martina" (profile of tennis player Martina Navratilova), December 26, 1982
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 26)
      - Transcript (Box 26)
    - Transcript (no Mike Wallace stories; Wallace introduces Andy Rooney), January 2, 1983 (Box 26)
    - "Soap and Hope" (the Amway Corporation, and the frustrations of people who think they can get rich by selling its products) Background/Post-Show (no transcript; see repeat, July 3, 1983), January 9, 1983 (Box 26)
    - "Who Killed Officer Neupert?" (the murder of a New Orleans police officer and the slaying of two suspects by the police), January 16, 1983
      - Background (Box 26)
      - Transcript (Box 26)
    - Transcript (no Mike Wallace stories; Wallace introduces Andy Rooney and reads mail), January 23, 1983 (Box 26)
    - Transcript (no Mike Wallace stories; Wallace introduces Andy Rooney and reads mail), January 30, 1983 (Box 26)
    - "The Devil is a Gentleman" (profile of Nazi mass murderer Adolf Eichmann), February 6, 1983
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 26)
      - Transcript (Box 26)
    - "Soldier of Misfortune" (whether a convicted murderer killed a woman in Oregon because of his post-traumatic stress disorder from Vietnam) Background/Post-Show (no transcript; see update, August 21, 1983), February 13, 1983 (Box 26)
    - "Harris Neck" (the fight of forty black families to regain land in Georgia they gave to the federal government during World War II, with the understanding that they would get it back), February 20, 1983
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 26)
      - Transcript (Box 26)
    - Transcript (no Mike Wallace stories; Wallace introduces Andy Rooney and reads mail), February 27, 1983 (Box 26)
    - "The Khomeini Years" (interviews with Iranian refugees), March 6, 1983
      - Background (Box 26)
      - Post-Show (Box 26)
    - "The Thomas Reed Affair" (Ronald Reagan's National Security Advisor, investigated for illegal stock dealings and forgery), March 13, 1983
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 26)
      - Transcript (Box 26)
    - "...Yearning to Breathe Free" (hundreds of Cuban refugees held in Atlanta Prison), March 20, 1983
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 26)
      - Transcript (Box 26)
    - "Man of Honor" (interview with Joseph Bonanno, reputed leader of organized crime), March 27, 1983
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 27)
      - Transcript (Box 27)
    - "Chlordane" (the controversy over whether the pesticide cause cancer), April 10, 1983
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 27)
      - Transcript (Box 27)
    - "Oraflex" (charges that the Eli Lilly company failed to disclose possible fatal effects of the arthritis drug), April 17, 1983
      - Background (Box 27)
      - Post-Show (Box 27)
      - Transcript (Box 27)
    - "Dollars Aweigh" (charges of fraud and waste in the US Navy's shipbuilding program), April 24, 1983
      - Background, 3 folders (Box 27)
      - Post-Show (Box 27)
      - Transcript (Box 27)
    - "Man of Honor, Continued" (interview with Joseph Bonanno, continued from March 27, 1983), Transcript, May 1, 1983 (Box 27)
    - "Charged With Murder" (ethics surrounding two Los Angeles doctors' decision to turn off life support of a severely brain-damaged man), May 8, 1983
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 27)
      - Transcript (Box 27)
    - Transcript (no Mike Wallace stories; Wallace not present, but Barbara Walters comments on Wallace, last page), May 15, 1983 (Box 27)
    - "Honor Thy Children" update (original air date: September 19, 1982), May 22, 1983
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 27)
      - Transcript (Box 27)
    - "Divorce Catholic Style" repeat (original air date: November 28, 1982), Transcript, May 29, 1983 (Box 27)
    - "Trouble Brewing" repeat (original air date: September 26, 1982), Transcript and Updated Introduction, June 5, 1983 (Box 27)
    - Transcript (no Mike Wallace stories; Wallace introduces Andy Rooney and reads mail), June 12, 1983 (Box 27)
    - "The One Dollar Misunderstanding" (the controversy after Yale University sold its literary magazine to a politically conservative editor for one dollar), June 19, 1983
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 27)
      - Transcript (Box 27)
    - "Good Cop, Bad Cop" repeat (original air date: October 31, 1982), Transcript, June 26, 1983 (Box 27)
    - "Soap and Hope" repeat (original air date: January 9, 1983), Transcript, July 3, 1983 (Box 27)
    - "Small Town, U.S.A." repeat (original air date: October 3, 1982), Transcript, July 17, 1983 (Box 27)
    - "Rational Suicide?" repeat (original air date: October 12, 1980), Transcript, July 24, 1983 (Box 27)
    - "...Yearning to Breathe Free" repeat (original air date: March 20, 1983), Transcript, July 31, 1983 (Box 27)
    - "Man of Honor" repeat (original air date: March 27, 1983), Transcript, August 14, 1983 (Box 27)
    - "Soldier of Misfortune" repeat (original air date: February 13, 1983), Transcript, August 21, 1983 (Box 27)
    - "Martina" repeat (original air date: December 26, 1982), Transcript, August 28, 1983 (Box 27)
    - "Oraflex" repeat (original air date: April 17, 1983), Transcript, September 11, 1983 (Box 27)
  - Season XVI, September 1983-September 1984
    - "Captain Jeffrey MacDonald" (whether the former Green Beret and convicted murderer was taking a weight reducing drug with behavioral side effects when he killed his wife and two daughters) (no transcript; see repeat, July 8, 1984), September 18, 1983
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 27)
    - "Anchorman" (evening news anchormen), September 25, 1983
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 27)
      - Transcript (Box 27)
    - "Crime without Punishment" (why the taped confessions of two murder suspects were ruled inadmissible and the suspects set free), October 2, 1983
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 28)
    - "The U.S.A. vs. General Collins" (Retired Air Force Major General Richard Collins, charged with embezzling $19,000in Air Force funds), October 23, 1983
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 28)
      - Transcript (Box 28)
    - "Jesse Jackson" (interview about his Presidential aspirations), October 30, 1983
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 28)
      - Transcript (Box 28)
    - "Whoops!" (cost overruns and mismanagement in the construction of nuclear power plants in Washington State caused the Washington Public Power Supply System to default on its bonds), November 6, 1983
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 28)
      - Transcript (Box 28)
    - "The Church and Nicaragua" (the alliance between some Nicaraguan Catholic priests and the Sandinistas), November 13, 1983
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 28)
      - Transcript (Box 28)
    - Transcript (no Mike Wallace stories; Wallace reads mail), November 20, 1983 (Box W3)
    - "Very Used Cars" (the practice of turning back odometers on an estimated seventy percent of used cars sold), November 27, 1983
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 28)
      - Transcript (Box 28)
    - "Helen Hayes" (profile of the actress), December 4, 1983
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 28)
      - Transcript (Box 28)
    - "The Coronado Mob" (former Coronado, California high school students who began by selling marijuana and built it into a hundred million dollar business), Background/Post-Show (no transcript; see repeat, June 10, 1984), December 11, 1983 (Box 28)
    - "Haiti" (the economic and political conditions under the rule of Jean-Claude Duvalier), Background/Post-Show (no transcript; see repeat, June 3, 1984), December 25, 1983 (Box 28)
    - "Camera Shy" (coaching business executives to answer reporters' questions), January 1, 1984
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 28)
      - Transcript (Box 28)
    - "Dateline: Damascus" (interviews with Syria's Minister of State for Foreign Affairs Farouk Al-Shara', Lebanese Druse leader Walid Jumblatt, and former US Ambassador to Syria Talcott Seelye on Syria's views of its rights in Lebanon and neighboring lands), January 8, 1984
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 28)
      - Transcript (Box 28)
    - Transcript (no Mike Wallace stories; Wallace introduces Andy Rooney and reads mail), January 15, 1984 (Box 28)
    - "From Pac-Man to Poker Man" (illegal use of video games in Tennessee and other parts of the country), January 22, 1984
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 28)
      - Transcript (Box 28)
    - "People's Court" (paralegal Rosemary Furman's fight to persuade the Florida Bar Association to provide low-cost legal services to the poor), January 29, 1984
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 29)
      - Transcript (Box 29)
    - "Over the Hill?" (a free Santa Monica, California clinic that helps the elderly to feel positively about aging), February 5, 1984
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 29)
      - Transcript (Box 29)
    - "Are They Really Bankrupt?" (South Tucson, Arizona, which declared bankruptcy after being ordered by a jury to pay $3.5 million to a disabled police officer), February 12, 1984
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 29)
      - Transcript (Box 29)
    - Transcript (no Mike Wallace stories; Wallace introduces Andy Rooney and reads mail), February 19, 1984 (Box 29)
    - "The Guardians and the Cowboys" (the Richmond, California Police Department, where black officers have testified against white officers in police brutality lawsuits), February 26, 1984
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 29)
      - Transcript (Box 29)
    - "Mobutu" (charges that President Mobutu of Zaire has accumulated a fortune through his corrupt regime), March 4, 1984
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 29)
      - Transcript (Box 29)
    - " Pravda" (the leading Soviet newspaper, with the world's largest circulation), March 11, 1984
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 29)
      - Transcript (Box 29)
    - "Nguyen Cao Ky" (charges that the former Vietnamese Premier heads an organized crime operation in California), March 18, 1984
      - Background/Post-Show, 2 folders (Box 29)
        (includes tape cassette)
      - Transcript (Box 29)
    - Transcript (no Mike Wallace stories; Wallace reads mail), March 25, 1984 (Box 29)
    - "Trial By Jury" (the increasing use of psychologists and other expert witnesses in selecting jurors), April 1, 1984
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 29)
      - Transcript (Box 29)
    - "Shirley" (profile of actress Shirley MacLaine), April 8, 1984
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 29)
      - Transcript (Box 29)
    - "Continental Airlines" (the dispute over safety between the Air Line Pilots Association and Continental), April 15, 1984
      - Background/Post-Show (Box 29)
      - Transcript (Box 29)
    - Transcript (no Mike Wallace stories; Wallace introduces Andy Rooney and reads mail), April 22, 1984 (Box 30)
    - "Very Used Cars" repeat (original air date: November 27, 1983), Transcript and Update, April 29, 1984 (Box W3)
    - "A Dirty War" (the search for the 'disappeared' in Argentina, victims of political terrorism), Background/Post-Show (no transcript; see repeat, September 2, 1984), May 6, 1984 (Box 30)
    - "Helen Hayes" repeat (original air date: December 4, 1983), Transcript, May 13, 1984 (Box 30)
    - "Whoops!" repeat (original air date: November 6, 1983), Transcript and Update Materials, May 27, 1984 (Box 30)
    - "Haiti" repeat (original air date: December 25, 1983), Transcript and Update Materials, June 3, 1984 (Box 30)
    - "The Coronado Mob" repeat (original air date: December 11, 1983), Transcript, June 10, 1984 (Box 30)
    - "The People's Court" repeat (original air date: January 29, 1984), Transcript and Update Materials, June 24, 1984 (Box 30)
    - "Over the Hill?" repeat (original air date: February 5, 1984), Transcript and Update Materials, July 1, 1984 (Box 30)